jetblueairways.com 2011-06-23

# JetBlue | Your Privacy

At JetBlue Airways, we respect your privacy. That is why we would like you to know how we protect the privacy and security of the information collected online on jetblue.com websites. Please take a moment to read the following questions and answers, which describe our online privacy and security practices in more detail. By visiting this website, you agree to these practices.

  * What Information Do We Collect?
  * How Do We Use the Personal Information We Collect?
  * What Information Is Collected From Children?
  * How Is the Information Collected Online Protected?
  * How Can You Access Your Information?
  * How Can You Opt Out of Marketing Communications From Us?
  * Does This Policy Cover Other Sites Linked From JetBlue.Com?
  * How Is My Information Handled If I Book A Vacation Package Through JetBlue Getaways?
  * In the Event of a Corporate Change in Control, What Happens?
  * Why Am I Asked To Provide Certain Information For TSA Watchlist Screening And How Is This Data Used?
  * What About Changes to the Privacy Policy?
  * What If You Have Questions or Concerns?
  * Note To Users in European Union and Other Countries with Data Protection Laws 

**What information do we collect?**

By using jetblue.com, your information and site activity data is collected. When you register with JetBlue's TrueBlue Customer Appreciation program online; book travel on jetblue.com, jetblue.com/getaways, or jetblue.com/companyblue; purchase merchandise through our website; or sign up for a sweepstakes or other promotional activity over our website, you will be asked to provide certain personally identifiable information such as your name, home address, e-mail address, and telephone number(s). When you use the online ticketing portion of our site, which is run by our ticketing agent, Sabre or the Getaways portion of our site, which is run by our business partner EzRez Software, Inc., you will also be asked to provide your travel details. If you book travel, purchase something from our online store, or purchase in-flight movies through our LiveTV system, you will also be asked to provide your credit card number and billing information. 

By using jetblue.com, some information may be automatically collected by our web servers as you browse our site. For example, our web server automatically collects information known as "clickstream data," such as the domain name of the site providing you with Internet access, the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your browser type and version, operating system and platform, the average time spent on our site, pages viewed, information searched for, access times and other relevant statistics. If you would like to remove yourself from these tracking and reporting functions performed for this Website, please visit the Omniture opt-out page at <http://www.omniture.com/en/privacy/2o7> and follow the instructions. We also collect information by using technologies and methodologies that enable tracking, such as "cookies." "Cookies" are small pieces of information that a website transfers to the hard drive of a visitor's computer for record-keeping purposes. "Cookies" provide visitors a personalized experience on our site by enabling us to determine unique preferences and trends based on visits to our website and to other websites.

JetBlue collects Internet browser tracking data through other technologies and methodologies that help manage online advertising. These technologies are provided by our ad management partners and enable our ad management partners to recognize a unique cookie, which in turn enables us to learn which advertisements and websites bring users to our website. The unique cookie, if it exists on your computer, was placed there either by us or by another advertiser who works with our ad management partners. If you would like to remove yourself from these reporting and tracking functions for this Website, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. and <http://www.doubleclick.com/us/about_doubleclick/privacy/ad-cookie/default.asp> and follow the instructions. 

**How do we use the personal information we collect?**

We do not sell your information and we use it only in accordance with this policy. We use the information to complete transactions, respond to your requests and notify you of promotions, updates, or special offers that we think may interest you. We also use your information to provide you with a more effective customer experience at jetblue.com and with JetBlue. In order to do this, we may process your information or combine it with other information that we have about you or that is publicly available. This enables us to customize your JetBlue experience and provide you with more relevant offers. To do these things, we may share your information with our carefully selected business partners who agree to appropriate confidentiality and security measures and who are bound to follow terms at least as restrictive as this privacy policy in handling your information. 

We use information collected from our web-servers and from site tracking to enable us to increase the functionality and user-friendliness of our site and to better tailor our site to our visitors' needs. For example, some of this information is collected so that when you visit our site again, the site will recognize you, and serve advertisements and other information appropriate to you and your interests. We also use this information to verify that visitors to our site meet the criteria required to process their requests. 

As described above, some of this information is collected through the use of "cookies". Most browsers used by visitors have options that allow the visitor to control whether the browser will accept "cookies", reject "cookies", or notify the visitor each time a "cookie" is sent, but setting a browser to reject "cookies" will limit the range of features available to the visitor on our site. Please be aware that rejecting or disabling "cookies" will not necessarily limit all forms of site tracking technologies and methodologies. 

To the extent permitted by law, we may disclose personally identifiable information to government authorities or third parties pursuant to a legal request, subpoena, or other legal process. We may also use or disclose your information as permitted by law to perform charge verifications, report or collect debts owed, fight fraud, or protect the rights or property of JetBlue, our customers, our website, or its users. 

**What information is collected from children?**

JetBlue is a general audience site and does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 without verifiable parental consent. If you are under the age of 13, please do not provide personally identifiable information of any kind whatsoever. If a child provides us with personally identifiable information, a parent or legal guardian of that child may contact us to obtain that information by sending an e-mail to privacy@jetblue.com or by writing to: 

> JetBlue Airways Corporation  
>  Att'n: Customer Relations  
>  P.O. Box 17435  
>  Salt Lake City, UT 84117-0435 

Or by calling 1-801-365-2470 if they would like this information deleted from our records.

**How is the information collected online protected?**

We take reasonable precautions to keep all information obtained from our online visitors secure against unauthorized access and use and we periodically review our security measures. When you voluntarily provide us with information while registering or booking a reservation, such as your name, address, phone number, credit card information, and travel details, your information is encrypted and transferred over a secure connection, available on browsers such as Netscape Navigator or Microsoft Internet Explorer. The padlock icon found in most browsers will appear locked and the first characters of the website address will change from "http" to "https" if you are accessing a secure server. Do not use e-mail to send us credit card, billing or other personally identifiable information as e-mail travels unencrypted and can be read by anyone who receives or intercepts it. Once your information reaches us, we store it behind a secure firewall that blocks access to the information from outside of our network. Only JetBlue-authorized individuals are allowed to access your information. 

**How can you access your information?**

You can access and edit any of the personally identifiable information you've provided to us by logging in to your TrueBlue Account and clicking on "Contact Information" or "Log In Information." All other requests for access to your personally identifiable information may be made by writing to: 

> JetBlue Airways Corporation  
>  Att'n: Customer Relations  
>  P.O. Box 17435  
>  Salt Lake City, UT 84117-0435 

Or by calling 1-801-365-2470.

**How can you opt out of marketing communications from us?**

While most of our visitors appreciate the services that registration on this site allows us to provide, we respect the right of each visitor to control how his or her personally identifiable information is used. If you do not wish to receive communications about special offers or programs, you can opt out when the information is collected by emailing us at privacy@jetblue.com or by clicking on a link provided at the bottom of the e-mail communication. Please see the section entitled "What Information Do We Collect" for instructions for opting out of the tracking and reporting functions of for jetblue.com

**Does this policy cover other sites linked from jetblue.com?**

In order to assist you and provide you as much information as possible, our site contains links to other websites including those that offer ancillary travel services, map functionality, and branded or co-branded JetBlue merchandise and offers. This policy applies only to websites and services that are owned and operated by JetBlue, including jetblue.com, jetblue.com/trueblue, jetblue.com/companyblue, and the air component of JetBlue Getaways (jetblue.com/getaways). Sites that are not owned or operated by JetBlue, including JetBlue Cruises, EzRez (the non-air component of JetBlue Getaways packages – see below), and cars and hotels are not covered by this privacy policy, and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other sites.

**How is my information handled if I book a vacation package through JetBlue Getaways?**

This privacy policy applies to only the JetBlue component of JetBlue Getaways' vacation packages. If you book a vacation package with JetBlue Getaways, your information will be shared with our business partner EzRez and third-party Travel Suppliers, such as rental car companies, hotels and other travel industry participants, which you are considering using. JetBlue is not responsible for the privacy practices of EzRez or these third-party Travel Suppliers and you should consult the websites of these companies to learn more about their privacy practices. Please see EzRez's privacy policy for EzRez's privacy practices at [http://www.ezrez.com/privacy.htm](http://www.ezrez.com/). 

**Why am I asked to provide certain information for TSA watchlist screening and how is this data used?**

The Transportation Security Administration (TSA) requires you to provide your full name, date of birth, and gender for the purpose of watch list screening, under the authority of 49 U.S.C. section 114, the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 and 49 C.F.R parts 1540 and 1560. You may also provide your Redress Number, if available. Failure to provide your full name, date of birth, and gender may result in denial of transport or denial of authority to enter the boarding area. TSA may share information you provide with law enforcement or intelligence agencies or others under its published system of records notice. For more on TSA privacy policies, or to review the system of records notice and the privacy impact assessment, please see the TSA Web site at [www.tsa.gov](http://www.tsa.gov/).

**In the event of a corporate change in control, what happens?**

Should there be a corporate change in control, through merger, acquisition or bankruptcy, we reserve the right to transfer information collected from you to the new party-in-control of JetBlue Airways Corporation in the normal course of business. 

**What about changes to the privacy policy?**

By visiting our site you consent to our collection and use of your information as described in this policy. We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy and related business practices at any time by posting updated text on this site. Your consent to the various practices described in this policy does not result in a contractual relationship with JetBlue Airways Corporation or any of its affiliates. 

**What if you have questions or concerns?**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, JetBlue's privacy practices, the practices of this website, or your dealings with this website, please contact us at privacy@jetblue.com. 

**Note to users in European Union and other countries with data protection laws:**

JetBlue is committed to protecting personal data to the fullest extent of its Privacy Policy, which appears below. Because JetBlue is based in the U.S. with many flights in or to the U.S., this policy is consistent with U.S. law and practice. JetBlue does not fly routes within Europe, so this Privacy Policy is not adapted to European laws. 

By agreeing to JetBlue's Privacy Policy, you consent to JetBlue applying its Privacy Policy in place of data protections under your country's law. That is, you freely and unambiguously consent that: 

  * Terms of this Privacy Policy, not your home country's laws, control how JetBlue will process personal data about you 
  * Data you enter on this website, and other data connected with your flight, will be transmitted to and processed in the U.S., a jurisdiction whose laws do not offer data protections equivalent to your home country's 
  * Sensitive data, such as data involving your health, will also be processed consistent with the policy below and transmitted to/processed in the U.S., a jurisdiction without equivalent data protections 
  * JetBlue processes data complying with all applicable laws of the U.S. and other jurisdictions where it flies; this means JetBlue complies with laws requiring it to provide passenger data to government agencies

Back to top

Thank you for visiting our site, and for taking the time to read this policy. 

_**LAST UPDATED:** August 12, 2009_

_**EFFECTIVE SINCE:** January 28, 2004 _
